# RAHUL MONDAL

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### CONTACT

+91 8777036966 rrrmondal12@gmail.com portfolio-website

#### **SKILLS**

Rust (Actix, Axum, Yew, Tauri) JS (Node, React) Python (TensorFlow)

MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Kubernetes, Docker, Okteto,

WebRTC, WebSocket, JWT, ProtoBuf, gRPC, Hashing, Encryption, Asym-Cryptography

## **EDUCATION**

Future Institute of Tech.

2017-2021

Computer Science &

Engineering

Sonarpur Sikhsa Sadan 2015-2017 Higher Secondary (XII)

Harinavi D. V. A. S. High School 2014-2015 Secondary (X)

#### **PROFILE**

Aspiring and versatile software artisan with a flair for AI and over 3 year of experience. Eagerly pursuing a riveting software development role where creativity meats innovation, to craft cutting-edge solutions and contribute to transformative projects.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Developer (RUST)

Digital Aptech Pvt. Ltd. | Oct.2023 - Mar.2024

- Successfully migrated multiple microservices from Warp to Axum, optimizing
  performance and scalability, and implemented thorough test cases for
  enhanced code reliability and automated testing.
- Single-handedly developed a chat-widget end-to-end using Yew.rs with technologies like WebSocket & WebRTC to enable Real-time communication, for testing one of the microservice, improving user experience and accessibility.
- Leveraged Docker and Kubernetes for seamless container orchestration, deploying applications using Helm charts, resulting in improved scalability and reliability.
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines with **Okteto**, streamlining development workflows for efficient code delivery.
- Collaborated closely with the client and a three-person team to build a reliable product, assisting in developing a microservice utilizing **gRPC** to establish WebSocket channels.
- Regularly participated in code reviews with clients and team members to enhance code quality.

Software Developer (Rust)

Rapid Innovation | Jan.2022 - Sept.2023

Developed and deployed a desktop web application from scratch empowering **Rust**, used to monitor remote employees worldwide.

- Utilized cutting-edge technologies such as Actix-Web (back-end), MongoDB (server-side), and vanilla.js (front-end) to deliver a high-quality product, where the frontend of the website version was created with ReactJs, which is now being utilized by over 200+ remote employees within the company,
- Implementation of the application has increased productivity of the employees by almost 20%
- which has had a positive impact on the overall performance of the company, which demonstrates the effectiveness and value of the application in improving workflows and enhancing productivity.